We're all familiar with the idea of climate change and how our planet is warming.
我们都了解气候变化这一概念以及地球正在变暖这件事。
Extremes in temperature have become more commonplace, making parts of the world difficult to live in.
极端温度已变得更加常见，使得世界上一些地区难以居住。
But one place where excessive heat is making life very uncomfortable is our cities.
但有一个地方，过度的热量正让生活变得非常不舒服，那就是我们的城市。
Luckily, innovation might be keeping a lid on it.
幸运的是，创新可能正在控制这一局面。
As thermometers record temperatures, sometimes above 50 degrees Celsius, solutions are being sought to cool the air in our cities.
随着温度计记录到有时超过50摄氏度的气温，人们正在寻求给城市降温的解决方案。
In India, for example, heatwaves and rapid urbanisation have led to a big rise in the use of air-conditioning units, adding to CO2 emissions.
例如，在印度，热浪和快速城市化导致空调设备的使用大幅增加，增加了二氧化碳排放。
So, architects, looking for a sustainable cooling solution, are reviving an ancient 'lattice' design, used in old buildings like the Taj Mahal, to construct comfortable, low-carbon buildings.
因此，寻求可持续降温方案的建筑师们正在复兴一种古老的"花格"设计，这种设计曾用于泰姬陵等古建筑，以建造舒适、低碳的建筑。
Yatin Pandya told the BBC: "Traditional architectural forms have proven their performance in combatting environmental conditions."
亚廷·潘迪亚告诉BBC："在应对环境条件问题方面，传统建筑形式的性能已被证实。"
In America, about 80% of the population lives in cities, and it's these cities that suffer from an urban heat island effect, caused by factors such as trapped waste heat, concrete structures and pavements absorbing the sun and tall buildings blocking the wind.
在美国，大约80%的人口生活在城市，正是这些城市遭受着城市热岛效应的影响，这是由诸如滞留的废热、吸收阳光的混凝土结构和人行道以及阻挡风的高楼等因素造成的。
Residents and developers have tried to heatproof these places by planting large trees that offer shade and putting plants and gardens on top of roofs that use vegetation to help trap heat.
居民和开发商试图通过种植提供遮荫的大树，以及在屋顶上种植有助于吸收热量的植被和花园，来让这些地方隔热。
And in Los Angeles, there's an experiment to cover streets with light-coloured material that reflects rather than absorbs the sun and so they remain cooler than typical black roads.
在洛杉矶，有一项实验是用浅色材料覆盖街道，这种材料反射而非吸收阳光，因此它们比典型的黑色道路更能保持凉爽。
But it's satellites in space that are really giving us the best picture of our over-heated cities.
但真正为我们提供过热城市最佳图景的是太空中的卫星。
Glynn Hulley, who is leading an image-capturing project, called the Land Surface Temperature Monitoring mission, told the BBC: "The data can be used to identify hotspots, vulnerable regions, and assess the cooling impacts of heat mitigation approaches."
格伦·哈利领导着一个名为"地表温度监测任务"的图像捕捉项目，他告诉BBC："这些数据可用于识别热点、脆弱地区，并评估降温措施的影响。"
It's already found how green spaces, white roads and water features, have helped prevent our cities from boiling over.
它已经发现了绿地、白色道路和水景是如何帮助防止我们的城市过热的。
But with excessive heat still posing a threat to our lives, more solutions are still needed.
但由于过度的热量仍在威胁着我们的生命，我们还需要更多的解决方案。